Hello everybody. Today I'm going to be
showing you guys how to create your
Laura data set.
I'm going to show you how to caption
them, which is very easy. And I'm going
to show you how to train the Laura.
Um this is all for Z image trainer,
which is in my opinion the best open
source model that you can use within
comfy UI. AKA for free. So, first of
all, there's a few things that we need
to go through real quick before we get
into it. I'm going to try and be as
concise and straight to the point as
possible through this to save on time
for you guys. Um shorter video. But,
there's one thing that you guys got to
understand first of all.
I'm going to explain things in a way
where you can understand them. If you
just want a quick video on how to do
this and
you know, a really shitty explanation
from some AI voice over [__] then
go find that video and watch it. You
will have a shitty data set, you will
have a shitty Laura, and you will not
make any money because your [__] looks
like AI. But, if you listen to me and
just bear with me while I explain things
and actually learn and understand, I
promise you it will benefit you a ton.
Okay. So, let's get straight into what
you will need. First of all, this is
going to be two video series here. Um
both of them are going to be
um aiming for like maybe 15 to 20
minutes each. But, um so this first
video here,
what you will need is $5.
Maybe $10. But, I'm going to show you
how to get
an extra $5 on top of a $5 deposit into
Runpod if it's your first time adding
funds. So, if it's your first time
adding funds and this is your first step
in creating your first character Laura,
um whether you want to make an AI
influencer, OnlyFans model, whatever it
may be.
Um
what you're going to need to do is
put $5 into Runpod. If you don't have
$5,
you probably it's probably ain't for
you. Maybe you can get a job or
something.
So, $5, you're going to need access to
an LLM like a chatbot like um Grok,
Gemini, Claude. I recommend Claude. You
can use it for free. All you got to do
is make an account, sign in with your
email, whatever.
Third thing you're going to need is some
time. This is not a 5-minute process. If
you don't have a couple hours, then
I'd go do what you have to do cuz you're
obviously busy. Um fourth thing that you
will need is my Discord. Everything in
there is going to be
um there's going to be basically just a
workflow for you guys to download um
to
get your data set generated. So, and
it's in three three in there. Um I'll
show you in a second where you can find
that in the Discord in case you are
[__] Um fifth thing, you're going
to need some patience. This is not like
again, this is not a 5-minute thing.
You can't do it. Sorry, go do what you
got to do.
Um you're going to need you're going to
also going to need to be able to follow
instructions. If you have ADHD, you
know, take your meds and let's lock in
for a little bit.
Um and you're going to need one
reference photo. So, this is the one
that I'm going to be using for
demonstration purposes in this video. Um
one thing I'm going to recommend to you
guys before we get into the technical
parts of it and get really going is
please just don't use a real person.
You're going to get sued um if you try
and make money off of it or if you start
making NSFW pictures with it. Just just
don't do it. It's it's it's dumb. You
can use so many different tools to
generate a image of a not real person.
It's not hard. Google it, you'll figure
it out, I promise. All right, let's get
into it.
All right, so
we're going to head straight over to
Runpod. Um it is I believe runpod.io
is the website. If that's not it, just
Google Runpod, you'll find it. It'll be
the first thing. Um once you get there,
you're going to create an account if you
don't have one. Now, this is your first
time using Runpod, you're going to need
to add funds. Like I said, you can add
uh like $5 I think. If they don't let
you do $5, they definitely let you do
10. So, um
just head over, uh put your details in,
swipe the card, and
when it asks you um if you were
referred, I'm going to leave my referral
link in the description. And if you use
it, you get $5 for free. So, if they let
you put $5 in
as a minimum, I don't know what the
minimum is to be honest. But, if if it
is $5, you can you put only that $5 in
and then use my referral link and you
will get a free $5. I will also get $5.
It's pretty clutch. You should
definitely do it. Um if you can do 10 as
a minimum, then do 10 and then you still
get a free $5. Um
So, yeah. Do that. And then once you
have your funds added, you are going to
look here on the left-hand side, sorry.
Um you're going to look at pods. You'll
see your pods here. Now, you're going to
click pods and you're going to see a
bunch of GPUs that you can rent. You are
going to rent a RTX 4090.
So,
you're just going to click that. And
then you're going to come here and it's
going to you're going to see a section
here where you can change the template.
You're going to click change template.
You're going to type in comfy UI space
manager.
Now, it's going to be this template
right here.
Comfy UI manager permanent disk. Make
sure that it says runpod/pytorch
2.4.0. This is the one you want. It
should be right up here if you type in
comfy UI manager. You're going to click
that, okay?
And you are going to not touch any of
this stuff. And you're just going to
press deploy on the bat. So, I already
have one open, so I'm just going to go
right over to that.
Okay. So, once you deploy the pod, you
should see something like this pop up.
Um you are going to have to initialize
um
basically the terminal in which you're
going to be able to type commands into
and comfy UI. So, this is going to take
a little bit because it's your first
time running it. So, you're going to
wait for that to happen. Um and while
you do that, you are going to go over to
my Discord and you're going to download
something called a workflow. I'm sure if
you guys are at this point where you're
training a Laura, you already know what
that is. But, if you don't, I'm just
going to um
switch over to my Discord real quick and
kind of explain it.
Okay, guys. You're in the Discord, you
just popped in.
What you're going to do is there's going
to be a get roles channel.
Just hop in here. Press these buttons.
Boom boom boom, you're going to get the
roles. Then you are going to get a free
workflows and you're going to see right
here. Download the data set generation
workflow with face detailing using only
one reference image. Boom. There's going
to be a file right here. This is the
workflow. What you're going to do is
click these three dots here, click
download, and you're going to download
it. Now, you're going to go to your
download folder once it's downloaded and
you're just going to drag and drop that
into your comfy UI once it's loaded up.
All right, so like I said, this is
probably going to take a while. Back
over to Runpod. Um
your pod is going to be initializing.
It's going to take a little bit. Um but,
you'll know it's done when you see in
this logs tab here um and you can open
that by the way just by clicking on the
pod. You'll see in logs that uh it'll
say start script finished, pod is ready
to use. And you'll come over to this
connect tab over here. You're going to
click Jupiter Labs. And if everything is
done, then you should see this interface
open up once you click on that.
Uh you're going to open up a terminal
here, which is on the bottom.
Now,
you won't have to do this, but since I
was just in here, I will. Okay. What
you're going to do is you're going to be
in the workspace directory by default
once you load up
Jupiter Labs for the first time. And you
are just going to type bash space
run_gpu.sh.
Okay? That's what you type. You press
enter, and this will start initializing
comfy UI. This will be fast. So, as soon
as this launches up, I will
show you how to open comfy UI.
You will know that your comfy UI is
ready to launch as soon as you see that
you can
it'll say to see the GUI, go to
this. Don't click this though cuz that's
not going to work. You'll also see
probably all of this, too. That's
another indication that it's done.
You can also probably just go over to
your pod in Runpod here and you'll see
comfy UI. And this is how you open it.
So, once it's done initializing in
Jupiter Labs, you're just going to click
this and it'll open.
All right, so we have
a blank slate comfy UI
considering this is maybe your first
time opening it. If it's not, then
you probably know more than what I'm
explaining right now. But, this is like
I said,
a general overview for people who may
not know.
So, what I'm going to do now is remember
that workflow that you just downloaded
from the Discord? All you're going to do
is drag that right into comfy UI. And
whoa, what's all this [__] Right.
So,
it's going to tell you that you're
missing some models. It's also going to
tell you that you're missing some nodes.
So, don't worry about the models right
now.
This is the node uh like missing node
notification here. What you're going to
do is go
you're going to close that out and
you're going to click this blue manager
button up here. And you are going to
click install missing custom nodes and
everything should just pop up here that
you need to install. You need to click
these one by one and then you need to
restart comfy UI. So, you're going to
click install.
And then wait for that. Click install,
wait for that, click install, wait for
that. Now, if
you do that and one is still missing or
something, just click used in workflow
down here on the bottom and that should
show
whatever didn't show up for whatever
reason there.
Once you get those missing custom nodes
installed, you need to restart ComfyUI.
So, if you go to the manager, there's
just like a red restart button here.
You're going to click that and you're
going to wait for it to restart. It
should take a couple seconds, maybe a
minute, and then you will have all of
the nodes installed. Now, we need to get
the models installed after the nodes are
done. So, I'm going to show you how to
do that.
All right, so after your nodes are
installed and your ComfyUI restarts,
it's going to you're going to refresh
the page. It's going to ask you to
refresh the page and you're going to do
that and you're going to see this.
Missing models. Okay. This is super
simple. All you have to do is copy
all of this, right? I'm going to press
control C.
And I'm going to go to Claude.ai.
Right.
I'm going to post
or paste that in there, the missing
models that I just copied from there.
And you are going to type this exactly.
I am trying to run a
a workflow in ComfyUI within RunPod.
I am missing these models from my
workflow and I need commands to download
these models.
Please put them in the right folders.
And search Hugging Face
for the exact download links. Okay.
So, you're going to send that
and he's going to give you some
commands.
So, this part is important. You need to
listen up.
One of the models, this model right
here, you need the access token for it.
Right here, you're going to see that he
tells you that Claude tells you that you
need to go to Hugging Face and click
agree to accept the license. So, you're
just going to click this link.
Open it.
And Chrome is going to die and then it's
not going to die. And there's going to
be something here that says gated model
blah blah blah blah and you need to
click
um
like agree or something like that. But,
I've already done that, so I don't need
to do that. You'll need to create an
account if you don't have one already,
so uh before you can agree to it, you
need to create an account. Make sure
that you don't just create some BS
account because you also need to
generate your Hugging Face token with
this account, so
after you do that, you can close that
Hugging Face link and step number two is
going to be to go generate the token.
So, you're going to click this link and
you're going to need to log in.
Okay, you guys should already be logged
in, but I had to log in because I have
not been on the website in I don't know
how long, but anyway, the second step of
the well, whatever Claude gave you
should bring you right to this page.
Now, you are going to click create new
token and you are going to put a name in
and then
[__]
Anyway, you are going to create a new
token. You're going to put a random name
in and you're not going to press enter
like I just did. You are going to check
all four of these boxes under
repositories right at the top here. Make
sure you have a name in and then you're
going to scroll down here and create a
token. This is free um so, it doesn't
cost you anything and then you are going
to have this little interface that pops
up and you are going to have a token.
You're going to copy the token. You're
going to come over to
Claude again and you are going to put
the token right where it says your HF
token. You are literally just taking
this entire thing right here and
replacing this part with your token.
Now, obviously, I'm going to delete my
token because I don't want you guys to
use it. I don't know what happens if you
do use it, but I'm not going to find
out, so I'm just going to delete these.
Okay. And then you're going to copy that
and then you go back to Jupiter Labs.
Open a new terminal
and you are just going to press control
V
and press enter.
So, that's the trickiest model to
download. Um
some models just require Hugging Face
access tokens. It's just how it is. Some
don't. Z image turbo doesn't. I don't
know why it this one does.
But, anyway, if you can figure that out,
then you're golden. That's probably the
hardest part about all this.
So, the one that you just put the
Hugging Face token into is going to
probably be the one that takes the
longest to download. So, after you paste
it into your Jupiter Labs terminal, you
should just see it start to download.
There will be a percentage in the
terminal. You can monitor how long it's
going to take to download and once it
hits 100%,
you are going to do the rest of them.
So,
in your Claude chat, you should see that
there's a VAE model that after you do
the diffusion model, which is the one
that has the Hugging Face token,
once that's done, you're going to do the
VAE. So, just copy that, paste it into
the Jupiter Labs terminal, wait till it
hits 100% and then do the same thing for
the text encoder model and then you
should have all of the main models
installed and you are almost good to go.
Once they're downloaded, you should be
able to just click them here in these
nodes. So,
obviously, you should see the Flux 2
Kline
model. When you click here, you should
see the Flux 2 VAE and then here you
should see the text encoder or the clip
model here, which is going to be Qwen 3
8 billion parameter.
Already, so we are very close to getting
this workflow running. Actually, this
workflow will run.
But, there are still two very small and
quick to install models that I need to
be downloaded. So, this workflow will
run um and it will produce an image.
But,
we need to install the B box model and
the SAM model that plug right into our
face detailer node. The reason that the
workflow will run is because it will
generate images through the K sampler,
but when going to pass the images that
are generated from this K sampler
through the face detailer, it will
recognize that these models are not
installed and it will just bypass this
face detailer and generate the images
without detailing the face. Obviously,
we want the face detailed um because
that will strengthen your data set and
that will make your LoRA more realistic
looking.
So, what you're going to do is you're
going to run this workflow
and you're going to see that these glow
red,
but your workflow will start running.
So, what you're going to do real quick
is you can stop the workflow just by
clicking the red X right here in the top
right corner. Just click that to stop
the workflow because you don't want to
generate images without using the face
detailer. And you're going to navigate
to the bottom left corner here where you
see a button. When you hover it, it says
toggle bottom panel. And you're going to
look for
something in this chat, in this um
in in-app terminal that says failed to
validate and then you're going to see
something like Ultralytics detector um
and SAM loader. It should be It should
look exactly like this in your chat and
you're going to
highlight it, copy it,
and do the same exact thing that we did
with our first error messages for the
models that we did not have installed.
So, you're just going to paste it right
into your Claude chat and you're going
to tell him
the same exact thing. So, I'll just
retype it here.
I do not have these models installed in
my workflow. Can you give me
download commands for them as well?
He may recommend that you download some
extra ones that
usually come with the entire package,
but
you don't want that. So, if he
recommends that you download like four
models, you see like four W gets here,
you're just going to tell him, "Please
just give me the commands for only the
ones that are missing."
You're going to just copy
that code block that he gives you
and you are going to paste it into
Jupiter Labs terminal again.
Make sure
you can see how fast they downloaded, by
the way. Both of those downloaded. Um
and guys, just make sure that you don't
accidentally close out the terminal in
your Jupiter Labs that is hosting your
ComfyUI because obviously then you'll
have to restart ComfyUI.
And if you ever get any error messages
like something doesn't download or you
get an error message in the terminal
trying to download something, literally
just copy and paste whatever the error
message is and send it to Claude and
tell him that you got this error message
and he will guide you through how to fix
basically anything.
Now, there is quite a few things to
configure within this workflow.
First thing is obviously, you can see
here this is where you're going to put
your reference image. All you really got
to do is just drag and drop your
reference image right into this node
here.
That's the reference image I'm going to
use like I showed you in the beginning
of the video.
Now,
listen.
Do not change
any of these settings. Do not change the
resolution of the picture. They needs to
be 1024 by 68
height and width respectively.
Do not change any of the steps. Do not
change any of the things in the sampler
or the face detailer. I have configured
this all for you guys. It'll already be
set up once you download the workflow
and drag it into your comfy UI. If you
know what you're doing, if you are a
smart person and you know what changing
some of these things does, then feel
free to go ahead and do that. But, I
have picked the best samplers and
schedulers and the amount of steps and
whether you should
um
randomly generate a seed every
generation or whether you should have a
low D noise for your face uh detailer or
a maximum D noise for your K sampler. I
already configured all that for you.
The only thing that you're going to do
now is
some prompting.
So, as you move your way down to the
bottom of the workflow here, you are
going to see a prompt list box. You're
going to see, first and foremost,
another important thing, guys.
This pre-pen text box where it says
describe your character's physical
features here.
You are using
a face reference image, right?
So,
if you do not describe the rest of your
character's body,
the
and and it's not in this pre-pend of the
prompt here, then it's just going to
guess and it's going to make crazy
different results all the time and it's
not going to be what you want. So, what
you need to do is you need to spend a
few minutes here and either go over to
Grok because he is less censored and he
will be able to generate you a detailed
body image of exactly how you want your
character's body to look or you can do
it yourself.
Just
remember, be detailed.
After a few minutes of telling Grok
exactly how I want the body to look, you
can also use reference images. You can
drag and drop reference images into Grok
and tell him to describe the body shape
and physical attributes of the body of
whoever whatever picture you want to
use.
Um
I have this gigantic prompt. I'm just
going to copy this
and I'm going to put it into here.
Now, this is the important part.
But, before you start describing any
facial features at all, you are going to
run
a generation and you're going to see how
the face looks. If
your facial
uh reference image is not giving you the
exact uh
results that you want, that is when you
are going to start adding facial feature
descriptions to this pre-pen text
prompt.
So, let's say, for example,
if you look here, I have
um
you know, I described her age. I told
Grok to describe her age and um
you know, the fact that she has, you
know, smooth skin because
what I was getting originally, it it
didn't look the skin looked
like that of somebody who's a little bit
older, maybe in their 30s or something
like that. That's not what I wanted.
So, I started to add things that will
make the skin look younger. And the eyes
were also not the eye color that I was
looking for, so I started to tell Grok
to describe the eye color.
So, those are the things that I needed
to fix within my prompt to get the face
uh that I wanted in my outcomes. But,
now what we're going to do is come back
over to comfy UI here and
make sure you have your pre-pen text in
there and you're going to notice that
there are some prompts already in here.
Each prompt is separated by no line
break. It's just separated by an enter.
You do not want a space like I have
right now in between your prompts.
That will cause
a random image to just be generated in
the middle of each of these. You want
them exactly like this. Now, this is
only 10 prompts, but you can see here
that the entire prompting box is
surrounded by different descriptions of
POVs and
you name it.
So, we have
high angles uh selfies in the box by
default. When you just drag the workflow
in, they're going to be in there. We
have eye level selfies over here, low
angle selfies over here, Dutch angle
selfies, full body front facing, full
body back facing.
So, obviously, the reason that you are
going to run the workflow first um after
getting your first rendition of the
pre-pen text is
because uh you obviously want to see how
it turns out. So, just run it. Let that
run through. You can see how they turn
out and then you are going to adjust
whatever prompt that you created with
Grok um accordingly.
All right. So, my first 10 of these high
angle selfies has generated. We can see
here that there's going to be two
batches. The first one is going to be
the unrefined face and the second one is
going to be with the face detailer. You
can go through on your own time and look
at the difference. There is quite a
difference in the facial detail um which
is exactly what we want. We want a good
quality data set. It is so important
that you have a good quality data set.
Your lower is only going to be as good
as the images that you trained it on.
So,
now that we have our high angle selfies
done, we can start to do all the rest of
these.
So, you can
come into this text box here,
double-click it,
and
if you need to highlight all of it, just
press control A. That will highlight
everything in here and then you are just
going to press control C.
Get rid of the high angle ones cuz we
don't need those anymore.
And you're going to paste those in
there.
Now, you can press enter.
Now, you're going to do the same thing
for the low angle selfies. Double-click,
control A, control C,
and then control V in the text box
prompt. Make sure there are no line
spaces in between these prompts.
Same thing with the Dutch angle.
Control A, control C.
Boom, paste those in there. Same with
these.
Control A, control C.
Press enter, paste them in there.
And same with these. Control A, control
C.
Into the giant prompt box. And what
you're going to do now is
just run all of these prompts. This is
going to take a while. There is a lot of
generations going on here.
But, one thing I want to point out that
you don't want to start doing yet is
coming through these and downloading
them one by one. We are not going to use
all of these. Some of them aren't going
to look the best. Some of them are going
to be [__] up. But, that's fine. Do
not worry about it right now.
There is going to be a super easy way to
comb through all of them and, by the
way,
this node right here
is creating a file, a picture, a PNG
file, which is just, you know, an image
um
of our
picture, right? For example,
these, but it's also creating a caption
file, a .txt,
next to all of these pictures. And I
will show you where to find them after
this generation is finished.
So, what does the caption have? Well, it
just has all of these short little
descriptions, which is exactly what you
want for your data set training. You
don't want to describe physical features
in your data set
captions. You don't want to describe
anything that the lower is going to
train from the pictures. You just want
to describe what is going on in the
image, not the character.
So, we're going to let this run. We're
going to get all these, probably close
to 100 or maybe even more images,
generated and then I will show you guys
how to download all of these images with
the text files as soon as this is done.
All right, guys. Last step for the
video. After you have generated a ton of
images and you like the results of
most of them,
at least half of them,
you are going to head over to your
Jupiter Labs. Now, just a quick
disclaimer. If you do not like them,
then adjust your prompting. I promise it
is a prompting issue. It is not a
settings issue. Don't go changing [__]
because you're just going to end up
spending a bunch of time
fixing whatever you changed because
unless you know what you're doing,
you're going to [__] something up.
Just edit your prompts.
All right. So, like I said, go over to
Jupiter Labs once you have generated all
of your images.
Okay. If you're starting from just this
workspace folder, which this is where
you should be on the left-hand side
here, you will see a folder named comfy
UI. You're going to double-click that.
Okay? And you're going to see a bunch of
folders. You're going to look for the
folder called output. You're going to
double-click that.
And you're going to see a ton
of picture files
with
text files with them.
So, for example,
we have this image here. You can
double-click it. It'll open up the image
and then right below it, we have a text
file that we can also double-click and
we can see that it is just a caption.
Perfect. All right. What we are going to
do is come back to the comfy UI folder.
You can just click on it right up here
and you are going to find the output
folder again.
You're going to right-click it, download
as an archive, not current folder.
Download as an archive.
If If do current folder, you will
download your entire comfy UI workspace
and you do not want to do that.
So, I downloaded it.
You're just going to wait for that to
download. And once it does, it should
put a zip file into your downloads
folder on your computer.
And you are going to
open up that zip folder, which you
cannot see, but I am doing that right
now.
Open it up.
Unzip it.
Remember where you unzip it to, whatever
location on your computer that you unzip
it to, you can send it to your desktop
or wherever.
And after you do that, you are going to
click on the next video, which will be
in description.
Um and we are I'm going to show you
exactly how to
configure the environment where you're
going to train your Laura and how to
comb through your data set. Don't do it
yet. Don't go through the data set. I
know you want to look at them. I know
you want to get rid of the ones that you
don't want, and we are going to do that
in the next video.
See you guys there.